# **Matt Warman**

#### LINKEDIN.COM/IN/MKWARMAN | MKWARMAN.COM

### **PROFILE:**

Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer with a wide range of experience. Premier software quality and innovative problem solving are my top priorities. I view every challenge requiring creative and precise solutions as a unique opportunity to improve.

#### **SKILLS**

- Software development from idea to design, development and testing, then production and support
- · Backend technologies including: Node.js, Express, C# .NET (ASP, Framework, and Core), Python, and Java
- Frontend technologies including: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, AngularJS, and jQuery
- · Database development and optimization, experience with MongoDB, SQL Server, Postgres, and more
- Mobile development using Ionic, Swift (Xcode) and Kotlin (Android Studio)
- Development utilities: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Octopus, TeamCity, Kibana, DataDog, WinDbg, and more

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - SPECIALIST, WILQO, REMOTE - OCT 2023-PRESENT

Coordinated with specialist team and lead feature teams to design and implement new technologies to power Wilqo's Performance Optimization Platform, "Charlie". Designed dynamic data flow frameworks to power rich, tenanted, UI features. Developed backend services with configurable rule support to provide regulatory compliance. Led feature teams as architecture team liaison, mentored via knowledge transfers and development feedback. Used technologies including C# .NET, Azure, Typescript, Javascript, Python, MongoDb, Postgres, and more.

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ZEAL, REMOTE - JAN 2023-SEP 2023

Developed payroll API solutions for customer and internal usage using Node.js with Express and Typescript. Built frontend white label solutions to enable rapid customer success and easy use of Zeal's payroll solutions using React and internal UI suites. Deployed to AWS using Jenkins and custom pipelines. Designed and developed new feature suites along with product teams to enable customer success and attract new clients.

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PAYLOCITY, REMOTE - DEC 2018-DEC 2023

Developed time and labor management solutions using C#, React, AngularJS, Less, Ionic, and SQL Server. Modernized legacy solutions to incorporate RESTful microservice and CQRS patterns, utilize event-driven processing, optimize and scale performance, and improve UX. Performed penetration testing as appsec liaison. Triaged incidents using logs, dashboards, and memdump analysis via WinDbg. Lead development of multiple initiatives and new features. Mentored team members 1-on-1, through knowledge sharing, and via code reviews.

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER, KABBAGE, ATLANTA GA – MAY 2017-DEC 2018

Built and maintained fintech software solutions for the most valuable startup in Georgia. Stabilized platform technologies and microservices written in C#, ASP.NET, and SQL Server. Developed internal management suites written in Python and Angular. Updated and built new full stack applications using AWS, Postgres, C#, .NET Core, Node, Angular, and React.

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER, THE HOME DEPOT, ATLANTA GA - SEP 2015-MAY 2017

Started as Junior Java Developer and promoted through Senior Software Engineer. Constructed and maintained payment applications written in JavaScript, with AngularJS and Redux using Pivotal Cloud Foundry. Updated legacy Informix 4GL code to Java 8 RESTful Microservices with SQL database integration. Used modern development practices including Agile, XP, TDD, and CI.

# IT SPECIALIST, POLYMER SOLUTIONS; CHRISTIANSBURG, VA - MAY 2013-AUG 2015

Implemented and maintained computer systems for users and laboratory equipment conducting polymer analysis. Maintained production website, implemented design and security updates. Performed all duties in compliance with FDA Regulations and ISO 17025 (Compliant with ISO 9001).

#### **EDUCATION**

Kennesaw State University - Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, 2021